Joel Reid

92, Fieldgate Drive Ottawa, ON, K2J1T9 613-823-9548 joelreid116@gmail.com

Personal Profile

Creative digital media specialist with over seven years of video production experience and three years of graphic design experience. Uses SEO knowledge to produce content for various target audiences and brands. Excellent collaborative skills; spirited team-player with strong verbal & written communication abilities. Competent French speaker; awarded Diplôme d'études en langue française(or DELF) diploma.

Relevant Experience

Instructor - Real Programming 4 Kids

September 2019- June 2020 | Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

- Taught a computer programming curriculum to students (ages 6-18)
- Classrooms ranged between 1-4 students per instructor; between 1-2 hours per course
- Evaluated each student based on their programming proficiency
- Maintained a safe environment for all students and staff

Team Lead - Osgoode Township Museum

January 2021- Present | Loon Digital | Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

- Overseeing a team of creative media designers
- Serves as creative guide for all deliverables
- Producing motion graphic videos
- Designing infographic posters and brochures

Additional Experience

Assistant Director – Video Vignette Series

June 2018 - September 2018 | Families Matter Cooperative | Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

- Operated camera equipment for internal and external shoots
- Improved filming techniques that met client's standards
- Organized and logged video files for post-production process
- Troubleshooted equipment issues in order to continue filming

Education

Interactive Multimedia Management – Ontario College Graduate Certificate – Present

School of Media & Design | Algonquin College | Ottawa, Ontario

Media Production & Design—Bachelors Partial Completion

School of Journalism and Communication/ School of IT | Carleton University | Ottawa, Ontario

Journalism – Bachelors Partial Completion

School of Journalism | Carleton University | Ottawa, Ontario

Affiliations

Graphic Designers of Canada | Ottawa, Ontario

Technical Skills

Photography	Adobe CC Master Collection	Computer Programming
	Premiere ProAfter EffectsIllustratorPhotoshop	PythonC-LanguageJavaScriptPHP
Videography	Web Development HTML CSS JavaScript PHP	Music Production Ableton Analog Lab Audition

Interests

- Hiking (photographing wildlife)
- Creating content for personal social media accounts
- Playing guitar & keyboard

References

Available upon request.